[
  {
    "id": 1,
    "question": "What is the correct indirect form of : He said, “You had better see a doctor.”",
    "options": [
      "He advised him to see a doctor",
      "He advised that he should see a doctor",
      "He suggested that he had seen a doctor",
      "He proposed to see a doctor"
    ],
    "answer": "He advised him to see a doctor"
  },
  {
    "id": 2,
    "question": "Identify the word that remains same in plural form:",
    "options": ["deer", "horse", "elephant", "tiger"],
    "answer": "deer"
  },
  {
    "id": 3,
    "question": "যদি ICE : COLDNESS হয়, তবে EARTH : ?",
    "options": ["weight", "jungle", "sea", "gravity"],
    "answer": "gravity"
  },
  {
    "id": 4,
    "question": "Which word is correct?",
    "options": ["Furnitures", "Informations", "Sceneries", "Proceeds"],
    "answer": "Proceeds"
  },
  {
    "id": 5,
    "question": "The word ‘flying’ in the sentence ‘Look at the flying bird’ is a:",
    "options": ["gerund", "participle", "verbal noun", "gerundial infinitive"],
    "answer": "participle"
  },
  {
    "id": 6,
    "question": "Identify the determiner in the sentence ‘Bring me that book’",
    "options": ["bring", "me", "that", "book"],
    "answer": "that"
  },
  {
    "id": 7,
    "question": "‘A Passage to India’ is written by:",
    "options": [
      "E. M. Forster",
      "Nirad C. Chaudhuri",
      "Rudyard Kipling",
      "Walt Whitman"
    ],
    "answer": "E. M. Forster"
  },
  {
    "id": 8,
    "question": "What is the meaning of musk?",
    "options": [
      "a form of drama",
      "a face cover",
      "a substance used in making perfume",
      "a disguise"
    ],
    "answer": "a substance used in making perfume"
  },
  {
    "id": 9,
    "question": "অনুকম্পা শব্দের ইংরেজি কোনটি?",
    "options": ["Clemency", "Enthral", "Erudition", "Fathom"],
    "answer": "Clemency"
  },
  {
    "id": 10,
    "question": "Identify the correctly spelled one:",
    "options": ["Cesarean", "caeserean", "ciserian", "scissorian"],
    "answer": "Cesarean"
  },
  {
    "id": 11,
    "question": "What is the function of a topic sentence?",
    "options": [
      "to introduce the topic",
      "to analyse the topic",
      "to present the main idea",
      "to expand the idea"
    ],
    "answer": "to present the main idea"
  },
  {
    "id": 12,
    "question": "Who wrote Dr. Zivago?",
    "options": [
      "Maxim Gorky",
      "Boris Pastornak",
      "Fyodor Dostoevsky",
      "Leo Tolstoy"
    ],
    "answer": "Boris Pastornak"
  },
  {
    "id": 13,
    "question": "Would you please find out Bangladesh ___ the map.",
    "options": ["in", "on", "over", "at"],
    "answer": "on"
  },
  {
    "id": 14,
    "question": "Hasan has read most of the ___ of Shakespeare:",
    "options": ["poem", "play", "drama", "works"],
    "answer": "works"
  },
  {
    "id": 15,
    "question": "‘For God’s sake, hold your tongue and let me love’ occurs in a novel by:",
    "options": [
      "Jane Austen",
      "Syed Waliullah",
      "Somerset Maugham",
      "Rabindranath Tagore"
    ],
    "answer": "Rabindranath Tagore"
  },
  {
    "id": 16,
    "question": "Complete the sentence: If I were you, I ____ take the money:",
    "options": ["shall", "will", "would", "may"],
    "answer": "would"
  },
  {
    "id": 17,
    "question": "Go and catch the falling star. Here the ‘falling’ is",
    "options": ["an adverb", "a preposition", "an adjective", "a verb"],
    "answer": "an adjective"
  },
  {
    "id": 18,
    "question": "Fill in the gap with the correct form of verb: The police ___ informed yesterday.",
    "options": ["is", "are", "was", "were"],
    "answer": "were"
  },
  {
    "id": 19,
    "question": "‘Giving someone the cold shoulder’ means-",
    "options": [
      "to torture somebody",
      "to harm someone",
      "to appreciate someone",
      "to ignore somebody"
    ],
    "answer": "to ignore somebody"
  },
  {
    "id": 20,
    "question": "‘September on the Jessore Road’ is written by:",
    "options": [
      "Madhusudan Dutt",
      "Allen Ginsberg",
      "Kaiser Huq",
      "Vikram Seth"
    ],
    "answer": "Allen Ginsberg"
  },
  {
    "id": 21,
    "question": "Liza had given me two:",
    "options": [
      "pair of jean",
      "pairs of jean",
      "pair of jeans",
      "pairs of jeans"
    ],
    "answer": "pairs of jeans"
  }
]
